Cynthia Huallanca

cynthiahuallanca@gmail.com | +1 (305) 804-5510 | 17205 SW 88 Avenue Palmetto Bay, FL 33157 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cynthiahuallanca/ | GitHub: https://github.com/cynthiahuallanca/Portfolio | Website: https://cynthiahuallanca.github.io/ch/

Summary

Story-teller Data Analyst with experience working in cross-functional teams with passion for transforming large data into new easy-to-read scopes. Experienced in Excel, VBA, Python, SQL & HTML. An insatiable learner who loves acquiring new skills, tackling new challenges and overcoming expectations.

Technical Skills

Tools: Advanced Statistics, API Interactions, HTML /CSS (Bootstrap), JavaScript (D3.js, Leaflet.js), R, Power BI, Python (NumPy, Pandas, etc.), VBA.

Databases: Excel, GitHub, HubSpot CRM), NoSQL (MongoDB), SQL.

Languages: Fluency in Spanish and English.

Experience

ESDINAMICO CIA. LTDA.

Data Analyst Consultant| Ecuador

March 2019 - Present

- · Offer insights and actionable information by analyzing and interpreting business data.
- \cdot Use business data with the goal of answering questions and solving problems. Design reports and dashboards.

DATA TECH USA INC.

Excel Consultant | Miami, USA

March 2018

• Designed and trained Sales team in 'Excel for Sales course' allowing to improve their revenue by developing an efficient work process and gaining knowledge directly related with daily routine.

AZTEC EXCHANGE

Business Development Manager, Americas | Miami, USA

May 2017 - June 2018

Responsible for generating new business with debtors in the accounts receivable financing industry and driving big volume customers to obtain the sale of invoices of companies in LATAM. Calling/meeting C-level to obtain contracts.

- · Best seller, US\$1.9million in 5 months, plus new business line in Peru with US700,000 in new revenue.
- · Teamwork with marketing, support with ideas/strategies for customer engagement, improving customer perception.

Senior Client Management | Miami, U

April 2016 - May 2017

Responsible to engage new market of Latin America by selling the ePayMe Platform Value Proposition as Financial Service including risk management, risk assessment and compliance of clients.

- · Handled portfolio of +200 customers with +40% of client acceptance with different currency type and cross-border business.
- · Developed techniques to increase new customers rate, based on market data analysis.
- · Supported It team with tests and business reports to update internal system and platform.

AMINORTE SA

Data Analyst | Santiago, Chile

June 2014 - February 2016

Responsible for extracting, cleaning and interpreting business and market data.

- · Collaboration in the creation of extracting data software to further analyze and gave directors new markets trends.
- · Transformed company data into dashboard of opportunities to develop client relationships

Project Manager (Data Migration) | Santiago, Chile

October 2012 - July 2014

Orchestrated an initiation, planning, design, execution, monitoring, controlling and procurement of the migration into new ERP, transforming users needs into technical requirements and vice-versa.

- · Restructured rigid processes and integrated them into the new ERP, decreasing logistic time process by 60%.
- · Process completed within 8 months, by managing IT team, including training personnel.
- · Cleaned, transformed old data to migrate into new ERP.

Cynthia Huallanca

cynthiahuallanca@gmail.com | +1 (305) 804-5510 | 17205 SW 88 Avenue Palmetto Bay, FL 33157 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cynthiahuallanca/ | GitHub: https://github.com/cynthiahuallanca/Portfolio | Website: https://cynthiahuallanca.github.io/ch/

Projects

Built 'Weather Data Analysis' <u>Website</u>, to compare the climate of 500+ cities worldwide with latitude/longitude, based on Application Programing Interface (API) of <u>Open Weather Map</u>. Some technical skills used were:

- · Python (Pandas/Matplotlib)
- · HTML/CSS (Bootstrap)

Education

UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI | Miami, USA

In progress

Business Analyst

UNIVERSITY OF CONCEPCION | Concepcion, Chile

May 2012

Bachelor's Degree Auditing and Accounting. Major: Science in Business Administration